innotas.com 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy

Planview and its subsidiaries respect your privacy. In order to provide you with relevant information and respond to your requests, we sometimes request that you provide us with information about yourself. This Privacy Statement informs you of our privacy practices and of the choices you can make about the way your information is collected online and how that information is used. Planview operates in the business-to-business software industry, and does not focus on consumer users or the collection of consumer data. To the extent we collect information on-line, our purpose is to better serve our business customers. Also, any reference to a Planview website includes all of our websites as well as those of our subsidiaries. As you read this Privacy Statement, note that Planview maintains these same privacy practices with respect to data that is collected off-line. This Privacy Statement applies with respect to both our on-line and off-line methods of data collection and use of the information collected. Planview complies with the Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from EU member countries to companies in the United States. Planview has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, recourse, enforcement and liability. To learn more about the Privacy Shield framework, and to view Planview’s certification, please visit the [Privacy Shield Website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/ "Privacy Shield Website"). This Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of third parties that Planview does not own or control, or to individuals that Planview does not employ or manage. You can request a copy of this Privacy Policy by contacting us at [email privacy@planview.com to request a copy of this Privacy Policy](mailto:privacy@planview.com "Request a copy of this Privacy Policy").

## The Types of Information Planview Collects

Some portions of our website may request that you provide us with information about yourself from which we are able to identify you. Examples of this personally identifiable information include your name, contact information (phone and fax numbers, street address, and email address), company name, work title and payment data. Some of the ways in which we may collect personally identifiable information from you are:

  * Product information requests
  * White papers or other downloads
  * Event registrations for Webcasts, conferences, seminars, etc.
  * Product support registration
  * Education registration

In addition to the information you provide, Planview may also collect information during your visit to our website through the use of automatic data collection tools such as cookies (described below) and other commonly used information-gathering tools. These tools collect certain standard information that your browser sends to our website such as your browser type, the Internet Protocol (IP) address by which you are accessing the Internet, the address of the website from which you arrived at a Planview website, and the date and time of visits. We may also gather aggregate, non-personally identifiable information, such as the number of hits to our website. “Cookies” are small text files that store information about your interactions with a particular website, either temporarily (known as a “temporary” or “session” cookie, and deleted once you close your browser window) or more permanently on the hard drive of your computer (known as a “permanent” or “persistent cookie”). Cookies can make it easier to use a website by allowing servers to access certain information quickly:

  * Session cookies can be used to help a user’s browser navigate a website more smoothly and may show up if the user comes from a website with which the subsequent website has some relationship (e.g., a website of an affiliated company) and can give helpful information.
  * Persistent cookies can be used to customize a website for a user, such as by storing passwords, preferences, and registration and account information so that users do not have to re-enter this information each time they visit a website.

Our website may use both session cookies and persistent cookies to store information that allows us to improve our customer service to you and provide you with the ability to navigate the website more easily. To make our website easier to use, we combine information collected via cookies with personally identifiable information. You can set your browser to decline cookies if you prefer. If you do so, you may not be able to access important functions or areas of our websites or enjoy the convenience of more easily navigating our website.

## Use of Analytics Tools

Planview also uses web analytics services, which currently include Google Analytics and Marketo. **Google Analytics** is a web analytics service provided by Google Inc. (“ **Google** “). Google Analytics uses cookies and similar technologies to analyze how users use the Planview web sites. The information generated about website usage (including your shortened IP address) is transmitted to Google in the U.S. This information is used to evaluate visitors’ use of the Planview web sites, compile statistical reports on web site and visitor activity, and provide other services related to the site and Internet use. Google may also collect information about Planview visitors’ use of other websites. For more information about Google Analytics, or to opt out of Google Analytics, please go to: [The Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on page at https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout "Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on") We also use first party analytics tools, such as **Marketo** , to assist us with certain automated marketing efforts from your interactions on our website, including information you may provide. We use this information to better understand our customers and potential customers and to assess our marketing effectiveness and/or business performance.

## Use of Social Media

We use social media widgets as dynamic information sharing tools on our website (such as **AddThis** , **Pinterest** ) to engage in dialogue, share information and media, and collaborate with our visitors. Your activity on these social media sites is governed by the security and privacy policies of the third-party sites. Planview does not control, moderate or endorse the comments or opinions provided by visitors to these sites. You should review the privacy policies of all websites before using them and ensure that you understand how your information may be used. You should also adjust privacy settings on your account on any third-party website to match your preferences.

## How Planview Uses the Information We Gather

The information Planview collects helps us to understand how our website is being used so that we can improve its quality and make it more helpful to our users. We may also use the information we collect about you to communicate with you about our products and services. These uses may include providing you with service and support, communicating with you and responding to your requests, and sending you information in relation to new products and services. If you do not provide certain information, you may still be able to access other portions of this website, although it may limit your access to certain information or services.

## How Planview Shares This Information with Others

Personal information collected on Planview sites and through our services may be stored and processed in the United States or any other country in which Planview or its subsidiaries or service providers maintain facilities. By providing the information via any of our websites, you are consenting to the transfer of the information outside of your country to any country (including countries which may not have adequate levels of protection). Planview shares information for business purposes only on a need-to-know basis and only with: its own employees and affiliates; the customer from which Planview received the information; Planview agents, consultants, subcontractors, and third-party service-provider companies, that have agreed to take measures to safeguard your information and other entities authorized to have access to such information under applicable law or regulation. Except as described in this Privacy Statement, Planview will not share the personal information you provide to Planview with non-Planview third parties without your permission except as required by law or when necessary in order to protect the rights of Planview or its employees.

## Links to Non-Planview Websites

This website may provide links to unaffiliated, third-party websites for your convenience and information. If you access these links, you will leave the Planview website. Planview has no control over these websites and is not responsible or liable for the policies and practices followed by third parties. The personal data you choose to provide to or that is collected by these third parties is not covered by this Privacy Statement. If you link to or otherwise visit any other websites managed by third parties, we encourage you to review the privacy policies posted at those sites before submitting your personal information.

## How Planview Keeps Your Personal Information Secure

Planview is committed to protecting the security of your personal information. We use a variety of appropriate physical, technical and administrative procedures to safeguard the information we collect – to process information only in ways compatible with the purpose for which it was collected; to carefully protect it from unauthorized access, disclosure, or alteration; and to maintain data accuracy. When collecting or transferring sensitive information such as credit card information, we protect it through the use of encryption, such as the Secure Socket Layer (SSL) protocol. Please keep in mind that while we have established safeguards to help prevent unauthorized access to or misuse of your personally identifiable information, we cannot guarantee that it will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Privacy Statement (for example, in the event of unauthorized acts by third parties that violate applicable law or our policies). In addition, if a password is used to help protect your accounts and personal information, it is your responsibility to keep your password confidential. Do not share this information with anyone. If you are sharing a computer with anyone you should always log out before leaving a site or service to protect access to your information from subsequent users.

## How You Can Access and Update Your Information

Planview provides individuals with the ability to know whether we hold information about you and, if we do (subject to certain limitations), to have access to that information and have it corrected if it is inaccurate or out of date. In certain cases, this may be accomplished by submitting a request through the [Planview Data Subject Access Request portal](https://app-eu.onetrust.com/app/#/webform/722e3c00-70f6-425c-b619-f0a700b4ce7f).

## Children

Consistent with the federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requiring parental consent. Any person who provides their personal information to Planview through this website represents that they are 13 years of age or older.

## Changes and Updates to this Privacy Statement

We may occasionally update this Privacy Statement. When we do, we will also revise the “last updated” date on the Privacy Statement. For changes to this Privacy Statement that may be materially less restrictive on our use or disclosure of personal information you have provided to us, we will attempt to obtain your consent before implementing the change. We encourage you to periodically review this Privacy Statement to stay informed about how we are protecting the personal information we collect. Your continued use of this website constitutes your agreement to this Privacy Statement, as it may be modified from time to time.

## International Transfer of Data

Your Personal Information may be stored and processed in any country where we have facilities or in which we engage service providers, and by using the Sites or disclosing information to us you consent to the transfer of information to countries outside of your country of residence, including the United States, Germany, Ireland, Sweden and the UK, which may have different data protection rules than those of your country or the country in which you were located when you initially provided the information.

## Contacting Planview

If you have any questions, comments or complaints about our Privacy Statement, please email us at [Privacy@planview.com (Planview Privacy)](mailto:Privacy@planview.com "Email Planview Privacy") or write to us at the following address: Planview, Inc. 12301 Research Boulevard Building 5, Suite 101 Austin, Texas 78759

## Planview’s Privacy Commitments per Privacy Shield, applicable only to Planview SaaS customers

Planview adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles ([the Privacy Shield website – www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/ "Privacy Shield")) when processing personal information of its customers using Planview Enterprise, Troux and Innotas solutions. Planview is committed to achieving and maintaining customer trust. Integral to this mission is providing a robust security and privacy program that carefully considers data protection matters. In accordance with the EU Data Protection Directive and implementing national legislation, the Planview Data Protection Agreement is intended to provide an adequate level of protection for Personal Data during International transfers within Planview systems made on behalf of Customers and under their instructions. Planview is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Planview also commits to cooperate with EU data protection authorities (DPAs) with regard to customer data transferred from the EU in the context of the cloud services provided by Planview (including Planview Enterprise, Troux, Projectplace and Innotas solutions). Planview, Inc and its subsidiaries are required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. Planview commits to inform its customers in the event of an information request regarding their personal information. In the context of an onward transfer, Planview has responsibility for the processing of personal information it receives under the Privacy Shield and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Planview remains liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if its agent processes such personal information in a manner inconsistent with the Principles. If you have a privacy concern regarding Planview or this Privacy Statement and if you cannot satisfactorily resolve it through the use of this website, please contact us as noted above. In the event that we are still unable to resolve your concerns, Planview is committed to cooperating to achieve a proper resolution of your privacy concerns. If a dispute is not resolved within 45 days or when not satisfied with the dispute resolution process, Planview customers have the right to invoke binding arbitration. _Last Updated 05/24/2018_
